freefileviewer.com 2019-04-03

# Bitberry Software Privacy and Data Protection Policy

Last Updated: May 25, 2018

## Introduction

This Data Protection Policy is intended to provide information on the processing of personal data in our company. It describes how we handle data which may be directly or indirectly related to natural persons (personal data). We also explain how we use cookies throughout our websites.

You can always access our free sites **without** providing us your personal information.

### Sites covered

The following sites owned by Bitberry Software are covered by these policies:

bitberry.com, bitberrycustomer.com, bitzipper.com, file.org, finalmediaplayer.com, finaltorrent.com, finalvideodownloader.com, freefileconverter.com, freefileviewer.com, freeyoutubetomp3converter.org, photohandler.com, photohandlergold.com, updatepatrol.com and urlp.it.

### Topics

  * Which personal data do we collect?
  * From whom do we collect your personal data?
  * Why and on what legal basis do we store personal data?
  * Who do we share your personal data with and why?
  * Who do we transfer your personal data to?
  * For how long do we store your data?
  * Which **cookies** do you use? Withdraw consent here (EU).
  * What are your rights?
  * How to contact us
  * Revision of our privacy notice

## Which personal data do we collect?

When you visit our web sites, we log which pages were visited, including the IP address of the visitor. This is necessary for us in order to combat abuse and e.g. mitigate DDoS attacks. These logs are accessible only by our operations staff and our hosting providers, and the information is never shared or used for anything but to ensure the operation of our web sites. 

We also store your IP address in **anonymized form** (we mask out part of it), and use this information for usage statistics and to improve our web site contents. We do **not** use cookies for this purpose. 

When you purchase a product from us, we need to collect your email address, first and last name, address, phone number, technical details (IP address included), geographic data as well as other data that may be required for completion of a purchase. We use your email address as login username on our Customer Portal, and otherwise only use the information to complete your purchase and to keep accounting logs as required by law. 

If you contact us for support, we will store your data in connection with this particular inquiry. We **only** use the contact details you provide to answer your inquiry. 

If you sign up for a newsletter, we will store your contact information for use when emailing you the requested newsletter **only**. 

We use [Cleverbridge](https://www.cleverbridge.com/) to handle online payment transactions and we do **not** store payment card information. Please note that billing and billing information is handled by Cleverbridge in accordance with applicable laws. 

## From whom do we collect your personal data?

We only collect data about you when you provide it to us yourself.

We do **not** collect or buy personally identifiable information from third parties. 

## Why and on what legal basis do we store personal data?

We are required by law to set out in this privacy statement the legal grounds on which we rely in order to process your personal data. 

We use your personal data for the purposes outlined above because: (a) of our legitimate interests in the effective delivery of our services to you; (b) of our legitimate interests in the effective and lawful operation of our business so long as such interests are not outweighed by your interests; (c) of the legal and regulatory obligations that we are subject to, such as keeping records for tax purposes or providing information to a public body or law enforcement agency; or (d) the information is required in order to provide our services to you, for example, in order to let you download the licensed version of software purchased from us. 

Where we are legally required to obtain your explicit consent to provide you with certain marketing materials, we will only provide you with such marketing materials where we have obtained such consent from you. 

If you do not want to continue receiving any marketing materials from us, you can click on the unsubscribe link in the e-mail or by contacting us. 

Your personal data will not be transmitted to third parties for reasons other than those listed below. 

We will only disclose your personal data to third parties, if:   

  * 1\. You have expressly given us your consent for this
  * 2\. It is legally permissible and necessary for the execution of our contractual relationships with you
  * 3\. Data transmission is based on a legal obligation
  * 4\. Data disclosure is justified by a particular interest and there is no reason to assume that you have an overriding legitimate interest in the non-disclosure of your data

We share personal data with the following recipients or categories of recipients for the aforementioned reasons: 

  * 1\. Employees (internal and external)
  * 2\. IT infrastructure service providers
  * 3\. Payment processors
  * 4\. Support service providers
  * 5\. Software service providers
  * 6\. Public authorities

Examples:   

  * [Zendesk](https://www.zendesk.com/) ([contractual commitment](https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/eu-data-protection/))- we use this service to handle support requests.
  * [Cleverbridge](https://www.cleverbridge.com/) ([GDPR](https://www.cleverbridge.com/corporate/privacy-policy/)) - we use this service to handle online payments.

## Who do we transfer your personal data to?

We use a global IT infrastructure including computers, cloud-based servers, networks, and software solutions of international companies to provide our services. 

These partners are based in different countries, partly also outside the European Union. In these countries, the same level of data protection is not always governed by and established in law as in the European Union. For this reason, we have taken a number of measures in accordance with the GDPR to ensure the highest possible protection of your personal data. These are: 

  * Cooperation with organizations in countries recognized by the EU Adequacy Decision
  * Cooperation with organizations according to the EU-US Privacy Shield
  * Cooperation with organizations based on agreed guarantees

Compliance with statutory obligations and requirements is guaranteed by our partners. 

## For how long do we store your data?

We will hold your personal data on our systems for the longest of the following periods: (a) as long as is necessary for fulfillment of our service to you; or (b) any retention period that is required by law.

In relation to our newsletters, you may request deletion of your personal data in our systems at any time by using the unsubscribe link in the newsletter, or by contacting us. 

## Which cookies do you use?

We do **not** use cookies for statistical purposes or to track usage patterns. We value your privacy, and only use cookies where necessary to provide our service, namely: 

### On www.bitberrycustomer.com (our Customer Portal)

It is necessary to use a cookie to keep track of your session which is protected by username and password. We use the cookie to time out your session, and it is a requirement for our customer portal to work. 

### On file.org

File.org is a free information portal, and we serve ads from Google Adsense on this site (only). The income from Google Adsense sponsors the continued development of the site, and is a necessity to keep the site running. 

Since the cookies are marketing cookies, they are not _technically_ necessary for the site to function, so we ask for explicit consent from our EU visitors to use them. Further, for EU users we only serve **non-personalized ads**. However, this still requires cookies to be set by Google Adsense to provide aggregate ad reporting and to fight fraud - the cookies **do not** contain information that can identify you. 

EU users: See the file.org cookie declaration [here](https://file.org/privacy.html#cookies), where you can also [revoke your consent](https://file.org/privacy.html#cookies). 

## What are your rights?

You have the following rights in connection with your personal data, subject to possible legal restrictions: The right to be informed, rectification, erasure, restriction of processing, portability, and object. 

We reserve the right to perform an identity check of the individual submitting the inquiry, in accordance with legal requirements, and to also take further measures to clearly verify the inquirer's identity. 

If you use our products and services anonymously, i.e. without having registered by providing your email address, we will not be able to perform the necessary and legally required identity check within the scope of your legal request. In accordance with Article 11(2) GDPR we therefore reject the exercise of any claims of the data subject according to Articles 12 to 22 GDPR, unless the data subject provides information allowing their identification in order to exercise their rights laid down in the aforementioned articles. 

### The right to request access to your personal data

If you would like to know what personal data we hold on you, you can see most of it in our [customer portal](https://www.bitberrycustomer.com/) where you can see and update information provided when purchasing software from us, including when and from where you downloaded the licensed software. 

[Contact us](https://www.bitberry.com/index.html#contact) if you need the information provided by email, but be sure to include information that can clearly identify you, otherwise we will not be able to fulfill your request. 

### The right to rectification of your personal data

You will find an overview of the records stored by us, such as your name and email address in our [customer portal](https://www.bitberrycustomer.com/). If you find that this information is incorrect, you can change it yourself. 

For all other rectifications, please [contact us](https://www.bitberry.com/index.html#contact). 

### The right to erasure of your personal data

Should you wish to delete your data, please [contact us](https://www.bitberry.com/index.html#contact). We will then erase your data in accordance with legal requirements. 

However, please notice that we are legally obliged to store certain data for longer periods of time (e.g. the retention periods for accounting documents are currently 5 years). 

Additionally, we would like to point out that we are able to block your data immediately but due to technical restrictions it may take up to 180 days to permanently delete your data, provided there are no legal obligations and statutory rights preventing deletion. 

Further, please note that after the confirmation of your deletion request it is not possible to restore your data, which means you will no longer be able to download software you hava paid for. 

### The right to restriction of processing

You have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Please inform us of the categories of data affected by your request and the reasons for your request. We will then look into your request immediately and inform you of the result. 

### The right to data portability

Please let us know in writing which data you would like to transfer to whom. We will examine your request immediately and inform you of the result. 

### The right to objection to the processing of your personal data

If you are dissatisfied with our efforts in connection with data protection, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the data protection supervisory authority responsible in your country. Bitberry Software's home country is Denmark, where the responsible authority is [The Danish Data Protection Agency (Datatilsynet)](https://www.datatilsynet.dk/). 

Please contact us at privacy@bitberry.com or using our [contact form](https://www.bitberry.com/index.html#contact) if you have any questions regarding the protection of your personal data or if you wish to exercise your legal rights. 

Address:

Bitberry Software ApS, Blomsterhaven 42, DK-4300 Holbaek, Denmark. 

## Revision of our privacy notice

We keep our privacy notice under regular review and thus the notice may be subject to changes from time to time. The date of the latest revision of the privacy notice can be found on the top of the page. Any new modified or amended privacy notice will apply as per the revision date. Therefore, we encourage you to periodically review this statement to be informed about how we are protecting your information.
